Eryn Craig

Web Developer

Bainbridge Island, WA 98110

206.319.8300 erynlcraig@gmail.com

Experienced web developer with background in design, team leadership, and customer service. Excels at web design and git version control, organized programming, communication with employers, clients, and coworkers, and building web and mobile apps. Trained in full stack development including CSS, HTML, Javascript, database structure and more. Very open to learning new languages and technology. Open to remote work or relocation.

Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, SQL

Frameworks: React, React Native, Angular, Bootstrap, Sass

Relational Databases: PostgreSQL **NoSQL:** MongoDB, Firebase

Cloud: AWS, Google Cloud, Heroku

Process styles and tools: Github, Test-Driven Development, Object-Oriented Dev, API configuration, AJAX, JSON, UNIX CLI, Linux, responsive design.

Other: Adobe, Data Visualization, Research, Problem solving

Experience

Self / Web Designer, Developer

JUNE 2018 - PRESENT, SEATTLE WA

- Collaborated with clients in person and via my website on custom pieces and domains
- Manage website and portfolio, as well as personal accounting and legal filing
- Negotiated rates and time frames with individual customers as well as corporate clients

Seattle Art Museum / Security Supervisor

JUNE 2019 - AUGUST 2021, SEATTLE, WA

- Vigilant and proactive Security Officer ensuring safe, secure, and orderly environments for patrons, staff & exhibits.
- Contributed input on functionality, accessibility, and success of curation of galleries on a monthly basis, as well as reporting any incidents and monitoring security systems.

Sunrise Medical Billing / Billing Specialist

JUNE 2014 - JUNE 2018, VANCOUVER, WA

- Communicate with customers and health providers on a daily basis in regards to problems with billing such as misstated billing codes, informing clients about insurance, accounts, and answering any questions clients may have.
- Balance accounts, troubleshoot billing and code errors, maintenance of web accounts and services.

Education

CareerFoundry / Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

MARCH 2022 - OCTOBER 2022, BERLIN, GERMANY

Training in Full Stack Web Development via immersion, including Javascript, React, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, MERN stack technology, server side programming and more.

University of Washington / B.S. in Arts and Art History

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019, SEATTLE, WA

Technical art and design training and historical education spanning from Ancient to Contemporary periods; familiarity with a wide range of mediums, digital in particular.

Development

myFlix

Worked as a full stack developer and designer of a web application for public use. Development included configuring an API, developing a search engine for a database of films, and designing and building the user interface based on user stories.